vaya.net.au 2016-10-20

# Vaya | Privacy Policy

**Introduction  **  
This statement includes:  
>    our _collection statement_ , explaining aspects of our collection and use of personal information  
>    our _privacy policy_ , further explaining how we manage personal information.

**Collection from third party sources**  
We may collect personal information from someone other than you, and you may not be aware of the collection, when it is not reasonable or practicable to collect it from you, and it is available from:  
>   publicly available sources like phone books  
>   other companies in our group that you may have dealt with  
>   third parties like our business partners, your authorised representative/s and wholesalers  
>   information brokers  
>   other telecommunication and information service providers that interact with us in providing products to you (eg overseas when you use a roaming mobile service)  
>   fraud checking agencies  
>   our dealers, contractors and other representatives that you may deal with  
>   our websites and how you use them  
>   various parties listed under _Disclosing personal information_ in our Privacy Policy.

**Collection under law**  
We may be required to collect personal information under the _Telecommunications Act 1997_ and laws made under it (eg if we supply a pre-paid public mobile telecommunications service, we are required by law to carry out an identity check.)  
We may be required to collect information, relating to an individual or a communication to which an individual is a party, under the ‘data Retention’ provisions of the _Telecommunications (interception and Access) Act 1979_ (‘Data Retention Law’).

**Why we collect and hold personal information**  
We collect and hold personal information because:  
>   we may need to use it to operate our business  
>   we may need to provide it to other parties in connection with our business  
>   we may need it to comply with the law, including the Data  
Retention Law.  
The uses and disclosures we may make of personal information are detailed in our Privacy Policy.

**Unavailability of personal information**  
If we cannot collect the information we need about you, we may not be able to supply the products or service you want.

**Access and correction**  
Our privacy policy contains information about how the you can access and seek correction of the personal information about you that we hold. 

**Complaints**  
Our privacy policy explains how you can complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles, and how we will deal with such a complaint.

**Personal information**  
This refers to information or an opinion about a living person who is identified or reasonably identifiable, whether or not true and whether or not recorded in material form. For the purposes of the Data Retention Law, it also refers to information retained for the purposes of that law, if it relates to an individual or a communication to which the individual is a party.

**Kinds of personal information we collect and hold**  
Broadly, we may collect and hold:  
>    _personal details_ like name, date of birth, gender, occupa  on and driver licence number  
>    _contact details_ like physical, postal, work and email addresses and phone numbers  
>    _financial details_ like bank account, credit card numbers and your billing and payment history with us  
>    _service-related details_ like your user name, encrypted password and service usage history, support incidents, enquiries and complaints  
>    _other details_ relating to special situations like specific health information if you apply for priority assistance and information about any authorised representative you appoint  
>    _Data Retention Law details_ (where that law applies) like subscriber and account details, service details, detailed about  
telecommunications devices, the source and destination of communications, the date and   me of communications and connection to services, the type of a communication or service and loca  on details.  
In any case, we only collect personal information that is reasonably necessary to support our functions and activities. If we cannot collect the information we need about you, we may not be able to supply the products or service you want.

**Collecting personal information**  
Unless it is not reasonable or practicable to do so, and in other cases allowed by law, we will collect personal information about you directly from you (eg when you contact us by phone or online, or at our premises, or fill in an application form).  
In other cases, we may collect personal information about you from:  
>   publicly available sources like phone books  
>   other companies in our group that you may have dealt with  
>   third parties like our business partners, your authorised representative/s and wholesalers  
>   information brokers  
>   other telecommunication and information service providers that interact with us in providing products to you (eg overseas when you use a roaming mobile service)  
>   fraud checking agencies  
>   our dealers, contractors and other representatives that you may deal with  
>   our websites and how you use them  
>   various parties listed under _Disclosing personal information_ below.

**Holding personal information**  
We hold personal information in hard and/or soft copy at our ofices and in other facilities that we own or license from third parties, like data centres. We take reasonable steps to keep it secure and to protect it from unauthorised access, use or alteration. Where required by the Data Retention Law, it will be encrypted. 

**Why we collect and hold personal information**  
We collect and hold personal information because:  
>   we may need to use it to operate our business  
>   we may need to provide it to other parties in connection with our business  
>   we may need it to comply with the law, including the Data Retention Law.

**Using personal information**  
We may use personal information:  
>   to identify you  
>   for credit checks  
>   to prevent fraud  
>   to supply products (including goods and/or services) to you  
>   to give you information about us and our products, and product owners  
>   for direct marketing – see _Direct marketing_ for details  
>   to improve our products, our marketing and our website  
>   to answer your enquiries  
>   to give you customer support and service  
>   to better understand your needs and respond to them  
>   to manage and plan our products and business  
>   to charge and bill you for products you use  
>   to collect payment from you  
>   to monitor, manage, test and improve our network and facilities  
>   to comply with various laws that apply to us, including the _Telecommunications Act 1997_ , the Data Retention Law and our obligations under any carrier licence that we hold  
>   for other purposes related to the operation of our business.

**Disclosing personal information**  
We may disclose personal information as reasonably required:  
>   to contractors and suppliers who supply or support us in:  
•    market research, sales and marketing  
•    direct marketing – see _Direct marketing_ for details  
•    identity and fraud checking  
•    credit management  
•    service provisioning  
•    installation, maintenance and repairs  
•    helpdesk and enquiries  
•    support and complaint management  
•    communications and mailing  
•    billing, debt recovery and credit management  
•    network and product design and maintenance  
•    corporate strategy  
•    legal and regulatory advice and compliance  
•    accounting and financial planning  
•    risk management  
•    otherwise providing goods and services that we use to operate our business and provide products and support to you  
>   to your authorised representative/s  
>   if you ask us to do so  
>   to our agents, dealers and members of our corporate group  
>   to our business partners and wholesale suppliers  
>   to other telecommunication and information service providers that interact with us in providing products to you (eg overseas when you use a roaming mobile service)  
>   to the manager of the Integrated Public Number Database, the Australian Communications and Media Authority, police, law enforcement and national security agencies and other authorities when and as required by law  
>   to authorised agencies under the Data Retention Law   
>   to organisation’s that provide credit or finance to us  
>   to persons who invest in or acquire all or part of our business or company, or are considering doing so.  
Some of these parties may be based overseas eg Philippines,India and countries where you use roaming services while travelling. 

**Direct marketing**  
We may use and disclose personal information to direct market to you products offered by us, our agents, dealers and members of our corporate group, and our business partners, where we think the orders will be of interest to you, using:  
>   post  
>   email  
>   electronic messaging  
>   social media  
>   targeted web content  
>   other direct marketing channels.  
Direct marketing may continue until you opt-out by calling the number in _Contacting us_ even if you are no longer our customer.

**Accessing and correcting personal information**  
Please contact us for these purposes using the details in _Contacting us_ below.  We shall process and respond to your request in accordance with Australian Privacy Principle 12. There is no charge for making a request but a reasonable administrative charge, on a cost recovery basis, may be payable before we agree to provide access.

**Complaints**  
If you wish to complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles, please contact us using the details in _Contacting us_ below. We shall:  
>   acknowledge your complaint within a reasonable time  
>    give you an estimated first response time  
>   allocate your complaint to a suitably senior staff member  
>    process and respond to your complaint as soon as we reasonably can.

**Contating us**  
Questions, requests and complaints regarding our Privacy Statement or our compliance with privacy laws should be directed to us by telephone on 1300008292 or email to talk@vaya.net.au.
